Silvio Savarese, Associate Professor

Computer Science Department Stanford University

office: Room 154 Gates Bldg ssilvio at stanford dot edu Mailing address: 353 Serra Mall, Gates Building, Stanford, CA 94305-9020

BIO

My group **Publications**

Silvio Savarese is an Associate Professor of Computer Science at Stanford University and director of the SAIL-Toyota Center for AI Research at Stanford. He earned his Ph.D. in Electrical Engineering from the California Institute of Technology in 2005 and was a Beckman Institute Fellow at the University of Illinois at Urbana-Champaign from 2005-2008. He joined Stanford in 2013 after being Assistant and then Associate Professor of Electrical and Computer Engineering at the University of Michigan, Ann Arbor, from 2008 to 2013. His research interests include computer vision, robotic perception and machine learning. He is recipient of several awards including a Best Student Paper Award at CVPR 2016, the James R. Croes Medal in 2013, a TRW Automotive Endowed Research Award in 2012, an NSF Career Award in 201 and Google Research Award in 2010. In 2002 he was awarded the Walker von Brimer Award for outstanding research initiative.

Education

- 2005: Ph.D. in Electrical Engineering, California Institute of Technology, Pasadena
- 2001: M.S. in Electrical Engineering, California Institute of Technology , Pasadena
- 1998: Laura Degree in Electrical Engineering, University of Naples Federico II, Italy

Professional Appointments

- 2017-present: Associate Professor (with tenure), Computer Science Dept., Stanford University, CA
- 2013-2017: Assistant Professor, Computer Science Dept., Stanford University, CA
- 2008-2013: Assistant Professor, Electrical and Computer Engineering Dept., University of Michigan at Ann Arbor, Ann Arbor, MI
 2005-2008: Beckman Fellowship, Beckman Institute, University of Illinois at Urbana-Champaign

Selected Awards

- Best Student Paper Award, at the IEEE Conference on Computer Vision and Pattern Recognition (CVPR) in 2016
- J. James R. Croes Medal from the American Society of Civil Engineers (ASCE) (2013)
- TRW Automotive Endowed Research Award (2012)
- National Science Foundation Career Award (2011)
- Google Research Award (2010)
- Beckman Fellowship, awarded by the Beckman Institute for Advanced Science and Technology at the University of Illinois at Urbana-Champaign (2005-2008)
- Caltech Walker von-Brimer Foundation Award for outstanding research initiative (2002)

Teaching

- Spring 2016-17 (Stanford University): Computer Vision: from 3D reconstruction to recognition (CS 231A)
- Spring 2016-17 (Stanford University): Representation Learning in Computer Vision (CS 331B)
- Spring 2015-16 (Stanford University): Computer Vision: from 3D reconstruction to recognition
- Spring 2014-15 (Stanford University): Mobile Computer Vision (CS 231M)
- Winter 2014-15 (Stanford University): Introduction to Computer Vision (CS 231A)
- Sping 2013-14 (Stanford University): Mobile Computer Vision (CS 231M)
- Winter 2013-14 (Stanford University): Introduction to Computer Vision (CS 231A)
- Autumn 2013-14 (Stanford University): Advanced Reading in Computer Vision 3D Representation and Recognition (3dRR) (CS 331B)
- Winter 2013 (University of Michigan): Special Topics in Computer Vision (EECS 598)
- Fall 2012 (University of Michigan): Computer Vision (EECS 442)
- Fall 2011: Computer Vision (EECS 442)
- Fall 2010: Advanced Topics in Mobile Computer Vision (EECS 598) Fall 2010: Computer Vision (EECS 442)
- Winter 2009: Image Processing (EECS 556)
- Fall 2009: Computer Vision (EECS 442)
- Winter 2009: Special Topics in Computer Vision (EECS 598)
- Fall 2008: Computer Vision (EECS 442)

Service

- · Program chair of CVPR 2020
- General chair of the 4th International Conference on 3D Vision 3DV (2016)
- Area chair of CVPR 2010, ICCV 2011, CVPR 2013, ECCV 2014, CVPR 2015, ICCV 2015, ECCV 2016, ICCV 2017
- · Associate editor of IEEE Transactions on Pattern Analysis and Machine Intelligence (PAMI), starting January 2016